Name: AVINASH ARYAN

E-mail: aviaryan77@gmail.com

Mobile: +91 9431210691

DOB: 10.10.1997

Address: Hardiya Bedauli, SP Imamganj, Patna 804426



SUMMARY

Total Experience: 2 Years **Role:** React Native Developer

Analysis Tools: Advanced Excel, Google Analytics **Mobile App Development:** React Native, Firebase

Web Technologies:, React JS, Next JS

JavaScript Libraries: Bootstrap, Chakra-UI, Styled-components, Moment JS

Other Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MATLAB

Deployments: Google play console, App store, Heroku, Varcel, Netlify

Version Controls: Git

Debugging Tools: Chrome Dev tools, Redux-logger, React-native-debugger

Designing Tools: Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, MATLAB Simulink, Basic AutoCAD,

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

COMPANY: Designs.Codes

React Native Developer- April 2021 to Present

Ride Sharing + Delivery App: Bare react native (Mobile app development)

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Developed bare react native, cross-platform user-facing taxi app for delivery and ride sharing
- Worked using packaging tools like NPM (Node Package Manager), Yarn
- Experience on reporting and tracking defects using Slack and Trello.
- Designed and build modern user interfaces to enhance application performance
- Build reusable components and front-end libraries for future use.
- Optimized components for maximum performance across a number of iOS and android devices
- State management using Redux. Redux-persist with saga middlewares
- Centralized API helpers to control and debug API calls
- Added Logic to use Client and Driver screens in a single app with persisting data locally
- Used modern packages for advance features to use in Google maps, smooth animations, beautiful modals, validated forms, star rated feedback and other components
- Broadcasted data with help of socket.io to use in multiple driver and multiple clients

screens simultaneously

- Added in-app chat features to Driver-client chat and Assistant chat
- For user engagement implemented firebase push notifications and toast messages for inapp notification
- Tested and Debugged using redux-logger, react-native-debugger with added colors and symbols to identify the issues in both node terminal (for multiple user) and chrome debugger (for single user)
- Integrated ESLint and Prettier for linting and build process.

Next JS website: (Frontend)

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Developed reusable code for future use and optimized web pages for maximum speed and scalability
- Developed and implemented front-end architecture to support user interface concepts

•

- Managed brand consistency throughout the design and maintained & improved the company's website by adding more features and functionality
- Created features to enhance the user experience while ensuring that the web design is optimized for smartphones
- Produced high-quality mockups & designed different prototypes and provided highquality graphics & visual elements
- Troubleshot interface software and debugged application codes to improve functionality and
- Used server side rendering features to optimize performance of web app
- Integrated Contact forms for queries and support
- Managed to use website in English and Romanian languages
- Experience in popular React.js workflows (such as Hook, Redux, Redux-saga)
- Integrate set for markdown files for blogging
- Designed and build modern user interfaces to enhance application performance.

Travel Planner App: Expo + firebase

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Developed Expo react native cross-platform user-facing Travel planner App
- Designed and build modern user interfaces to enhance application performance
- Build reusable components and front-end libraries for future use.
- Optimized components for maximum performance across a number of iOS and android devices
- Added Moment JS for Scheduling trip
- State management using Redux. Redux-persist with saga middlewares
- Centralized API helpers to control and enhance API calls
- Added Logic to use Client and Driver screens in a single app with persisting Data locally
- Used modern packages for advance features to use in Google maps, smooth animations,
 Carousals, validated forms and other components
- Broadcasted data with help of socket.io to use in multiple driver and multiple clients
- Used Firestore for real-time data management
- Added firebase for Authentication in App

React Native Developer(Self employed)- July 2019 to April 2021

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Developed cross-platform user-facing features using React Native.
- Build reusable components and front-end libraries for future use.
- In-depth knowledge of modern HTML/CSS and OOPS concepts
- Optimized components for maximum performance across a vast array of platformcapable devices.
- Knowledge of modern mechanisms, such as JSON Web Token.
- Experience in popular React.js workflows (such as Hook or Redux)
- Integrate data from various back-end services and databases
- Designed and build modern user interfaces to enhance application performance.

PROJECT: React Native E-COMMERCE - Full stack (MERN)

- Authentication
- Authentication should contain roles Admin and Buyer
- Login using JSON web Token (JWT)
- Admin Panel to keep watch on products and orders
- In stock/ out of stock features
- Admin can add, edit and delete products
- Add, remove from cart
- Simple and appealing UI
- Integrated modern technology like Swiper, React native Navigation 5, Toast Massage, Axios
- Backend Development using Node, Express and REST API, mangoose, middleware
- Database MongoDB Atlas

EDUCATION QUALIFICATIONS

*	Malaviya National Institute of Technology, Jaipur-(B. Tech in Electrical Engineering):		
		72%((2015-19)
*	Senior Secondary (Bihar Intermediate Education Council):	-69.80%	(2014)
*	Secondary(Bihar School Examination Board):	79.80%	(2012)

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Completed Multiple Courses on React and React Native on Udemy
- Completed programming and management courses on Edx.org
- Web Designing for e commerce business store Twigo.in
- Internship in Power Generation from NTPC Kanti, Muzaffarpur(Bihar)
- Secured **AIR-15223** in JEE-main examnintion-2015 among 14 lakh candidates appeared for the same.
- Secured AIR-19203 in JEE-Advance examnintion-2015 among 1.3 lakh candidate

appeared for the same.

- Stood 1st in Brain Hunt (Intra-college Quiz competition, Sphinx 2018)
- Ranked 2nd in Circuit Mania (Intra-college Quiz competition, Sphinx 2018)
- Bagged 2nd Prize in **GesellBots** (Intercollege college Robotics event, CACS 2017)
- Got **INSPIRE AWARD** from **MHRD** for the year 2012 as I had secured **99.69** percentile in my 12th standard Board examination.

PERSIONAL TRAITS & HOBBIES

- Self-motivated, Enthusiastic, Curious, Energetic and Adventurous, Team Leading, Tech
- Sports: Chess, Cricket,
- Hobbies: Gardening, reading tech blogs and trends